# **Software Engineer**

(347) 933 8355

ssahme21@gmail.com || https://github.com/ArcRiseGen132 || https://www.linkedin.com/in/sheikhahmed21/

### Summary

I'm an energetic, team player who helps people through technology and communication; my passion for technology and education has no bounds. I have both COMPTIA A+ and SEC+ certifications, with the end goal being cybersecurity. I am experienced in computer breakdown and repair as well as hardware troubleshooting and am currently attending Kenzie Academy for a full-stack software engineering certification.

#### **Skills**

COMPTIA A+, Sec+ Certified
Express
Mode.js
Mern Stack
MongoDB
Visual Studio Code
NoSQL
React.js
Peer Code Review
NPM/Yarn

#### Education

Kenzie Academy, Indianapolis – Full-Stack Software *Engineering MERN* (Oct. 29<sup>th</sup>, 2021) CUNY Hunter College, New York – *B.A Media Studies (August 2012 – January 2016)* High School for Health Professions and Human Services - *Advanced Regents Diploma* (2011)

### **Academic Projects (Hands on experience)**

**Kenzie Academy** is a UX and coding school, both online and on-campus, with the mission to teach and train future tech professionals. The school is accredited in the state of Indiana and is currently a part of Southern New Hampshire University.

- Create Connect Four in JavaScript (Project Manager, working with 3 others)
- Bug Fixing in JavaScript using MERN Stack for a custom application for Kenzie Academy
- Coding search bar functions, password requirements/verification, and login fields.
- Write code for basic shopping pages with user functionality.
- Act as Scrum Master and write backend code for a video game review and shopping website using Mongoose, Express, and Node

## **Experience**

#### Freelance Field Service Technician

June 2018 - December 2020

- Upgrading all components of computer hardware for consumers to have easier use.
- Troubleshooting, break/fix, hardware, software, operating systems, and network connection along with internet protocols.
- Independent computer consultant for Desktop and Laptop repair, maintenance and upkeep.
- Repair, maintenance, and troubleshoot PC computers including break/fix operations.

• Responsible for all desktop, laptop break/fix issues

### **Self, New York** - Private Tutor

August 2018 - Present

- Prepare high school students for the SAT, PSAT, and New York Regents exams
- Design curriculum to address weaknesses of students and create lesson plans to remedy said weaknesses
- Adapt to the needs of students and teach in various ways in order to reach academic goals
- Continuously update parents regarding the performance of the students

## **Smart Academia, New York** - Lead Tutor/IT Support

October 2012 - May 2018

- Taught 2<sup>nd</sup> to 12<sup>th</sup> grade students in preparation for Common Core, SHSAT, SAT, and Regents
- Recommended, designed, and wrote test prep packages for students
- Trained new tutors regarding teaching methods, computer maintenance, and client relations
- Performed computer maintenance, including network hardware, software troubleshooting, break/fix printer troubleshooting, and part replacements
- Enable passwords on computers to prevent non-permitted downloads and installations.